Rong Dingkun,
容定坤呀容定坤
you old fool!
你以为你自己很厉害
Someday,
在我看来
you'll be buried by women!
早晚毁在女人手上
Miss!
小姐
Are you alright?
怎么了
My stomach!
疼
Lie down.
先躺下
Blood!
血
You're bleeding, Miss!
小姐 你流血了
Doctor!
医生
You'll be fine, Miss.
小姐 你先忍忍
please save my baby!
你要救救我的孩子
Or I'll die
他要是有事
with him!
我也不活了
Dr. Feng,
冯医生
we couldn't reach Dr. Zhao to deliver the baby.
妇产科的赵医生电话打不通
Miss!
小姐
Go to the OR. I'll do it.
进手术室
- Yes. - Wait!
好
Can you do it?
你行不行啊
Listen,
我可告诉你
this isn't anyone's baby.
这孩子出了什么问题
Can you take the consequences?
可不是你小命赔得起的
If you're so worried about the baby,
现在要保孩子平安无事了
why hit his mother?
那当时为什么打孕妇呢
Whether she lives or dies,
反正不管女人什么结果
the baby must be alive!
一定要保孩子
They're equally important
在我们医院
and we'll do everything we can
大人孩子都是命
to save them!
都得保
You...!
你
- Let's go.
来 快
Careful!
小心啊
Come on.
快
Hang in there, Miss!
小姐 你忍一忍
They'll be fine.
一定要平安
Doctor...
医生
is it a boy?
是男孩吗
Is it?
是吗
I see.
明白了
Got it.
好的
How did it go?
怎么样
Is the baby out?
生了吗
Yes,
回太太
Ma'am.
生了
Is it a boy or a girl?
男孩女孩
A baby boy.
是个男孩
I have a son!
我有儿子了
Huang Shujun,
黄淑君
Rong Dingkun,
容定坤
we have a son!
我给你生了个儿子
But the doctor says
不过太太
and quite weak.
医生说身子弱得很
Now, he's in the incubator.
正在保温箱里养着
We should be prepared for his condition.
让我们要有心理准备
Go wake Dingkun up.
去叫醒老爷吧
Tell him
告诉他
he's having another son.
又多了一个儿子
Yes, Ma'am.
是 太太
I'm turning in my resignation.
麻烦帮我办理一下离职手续
You've only been here for two weeks.
你才来半个月
According to the contract,
按照合同
I can only give you five yuan.
我只能给你五块钱的薪金
I apologize for the inconvenience.
给您添麻烦了
Like that would make my job easier.
你也知道是给我们添麻烦呀
How am I supposed to
你走得这么匆忙
find a replacement in such little time?
让我上哪儿找个代替你的人去
Again, sorry.
抱歉啊
Shixun!
哥
You were on the night shift again?
昨天又加夜班了
I pulled an all-nighter in surgery.
通宵做了个手术
Go nap inside next time,
以后别在这儿睡觉
or you'll catch a cold.
容易感冒
I will.
好
Don't worry.
知道了
I got paid!
你妹我发了一笔横财
How about breakfast
请你去广州会馆
at Guangzhou Guild Hall? My treat.
吃个早饭怎么样
Sounds good.
行
By the way,
对了
I delivered
凌晨的时候
a premature baby at dawn
我接了个早产的孕妇
whose mother is Mr. Rong's concubine.
就是你们东家的姨太太
She gave birth
天亮的时候啊
to a son early this morning.
她生了个儿子
That family
要我说呀
is full of drama.
这容家确确实实是乱得很
Hey,
对了
was it she
这个姨太太
who had a problem with you?
就是之前和你不对付的那个吧
No.
没有
Her new-born son
她现在又生了儿子
will give her more leverage
恐怕日后在容家
in the house.
也会硬气起来了
Shizhen,
世真
I don't think you should go back
你这个时候回容家
to work for them.
哥实在是不放心
Shixun,
哥
I'm just a teacher.
我只是回去教书的
I'll be fine.
没什么不放心的
Yeah.
对
You're right.
是是是
I don't know why I said that.
哥都累蒙了
I'm sure you know
你自己的事
what you're doing.
你自己做主
Yes. Don't worry.
放心吧
Alright. Give me a minute.
行 那你稍等我一会儿
I'll go get changed.
我回寝室换套衣裳
Then we can have dim sum.
然后我们去吃早茶
Yeah, dim sum!
吃早茶
Be quick.
我等你啊
- Shixun. - Yes?
哥
How about that new dim sum place?
要不我们去新开的那家早茶店吃
Sure. We can have
行 你想吃什么
whatever you like.
我就陪你过去吃
Thanks.
好
Mr. Rong.
容老板
Mrs. Rong.
太太
Miss Feng,
冯小姐
what brings you here?
你这是
I've just quit my job at the hospital.
我在医院办离职手续
This is my elder brother.
这是我哥
Master,
老爷
Ma'am,
太太
he's Concubine Sun's doctor.
就是他帮二姨太接生的
Thank you for delivering her of a boy.
原来是冯医生帮麟儿接生的呀
Our whole family is in debt to you.
那你可真是我们容家的大恩人
Give him that.
来
Uh...
这
Just a little something,
图个彩头
Dr. Feng.
请笑纳
I came in haste.
今日不太方便
I'll thank you properly later.
改日再好好地感谢冯医生
- Miss Feng, when will you come back? - Miss Feng, when can you be with us?
冯先生 你什么时候回来呀
We miss you a lot!
我们可想你了
They've accepted my resignation.
这不是刚刚办完离职吗
You'll see me at home soon.
很快就回去了
You're a good teacher and funny.
先生教得好 有意思
We like you.
我们也爱学
Fanghua.
芳桦
Go ahead.
快去吧
I'll see you around.
回头见
- See you. - See you soon.
再见 再见
Go.
快去
Now, I see
看来
why you want to go back to teach.
你想再回去教书是有原因的呀
Those two girls
那两个小姐
are your fans.
很喜欢你
They're smart and diligent.
她们聪明好学
It's a rewarding job
要是学有所成
helping them
我这个当先生的
with what I know.
也是很有成就感的
They're all here to see that baby boy
倒是这举家都来看这小少爷
except for the elder heir.
唯独不见容大少爷的身影啊
It's very generous of them.
容家还真大方
This is almost
出手这么多钱
as much as my annual salary.
都快赶上我一年的薪资了
Mrs. Rong can
我看容太太在牌桌上
gamble away it easily.
随便输几把就是这个数
Just take it.
收下吧哥
It's a thank-you gift.
也是他们的心意
Alright.
好
Let's go.
走吧
Dim sum it is.
吃早茶喽
Yes!
吃早茶
Miss Feng.
先生
I didn't know you'd come,
怎么不告诉我
or I would've picked you up.
我可以去接你
My new place
搬家以后
has a bus to this street.
电车刚好到街口
No need to trouble you.
走过来很方便的
No trouble at all.
我去接你也很方便
I was surprised that you answered the door. Why?
怎么让大少爷亲自来开门啊
They're all out.
家里的长辈都不在
Mrs. Rong and Concubine Wang are at Lingyin Temple in Hangzhou.
太太和王氏去了杭州的灵隐寺
My father seldom comes home these days.
我爹最近也不回家住
We can enjoy
所以
peace for a long while.
会清净很长一段时间
Thanks.
谢谢
Try this.
来
Miss Feng,
先生
the first time we met,
我头一次见你的时候
I found you so relatable
就觉得你好亲切
like my elder sister.
像是自家的姐姐
I was fed up with Miss Gao.
早就受不了那个高先生了
She couldn't answer our questions
经常一问三不知
and blamed us for asking them.
还反过来责备我们好高骛远
Finally, Jiashang's done something nice
大哥这回总算做对了一件事情
by getting you back.
就是把冯先生给哄回来了
Knock it off, girls.
你们两个越来越调皮了
I'll check your homework later
我倒是要好好检查一下你们的功课
and see if you slacked off
看看我不在的时候
while I was away.
你们有没有偷懒
Oh, no, please!
先生饶命
We're always hardworking.
我们可是很勤勉的
That's true.
是呀
We've been studying
您之前布置的
ten new words every day
每日记十个单词
like you asked.
我跟姐姐一天都没有落下
Unlike us,
倒是大哥
Jiashang has
先生走了以后
practically given up since you left.
他就再也没有好好上过课
Then he'll have to do test papers.
那我可得好好罚他做卷子了
Yes, Miss Feng.
你是先生
Whatever you say.
听你的
Morning, Miss Feng.
先生早
Good morning.
早
Miss Feng,
先生
I'm turning 20
下个月九号
on the 9th next month.
是我的二十岁生日
There will be a ball.
家里会办场舞会
Will you come?
你会来参加吗
It's your big day.
二十岁可是个大日子呢
How could I miss it?
我肯定会去给你庆祝的
It's just that
只是
I can't afford a proper gift.
怕送不出什么体面的礼物来
Just bring yourself there.
你来就好了
No problem.
好
Now, can we begin today's lesson?
那我们开始上今天的课吧
Let's pick up where we left off...
上次讲到了
Passive voice.
被动语态
Excuse me.
抱歉
Sorry to interrupt.
打扰
I'll leave you two alone.
嘉上
Wait, Miss Feng.
冯先生
I'm here
今日之事
for you, too.
同你也有关系
What's up?
什么事啊
It's about the previous leak.
关于之前泄密的事
Mr. Zhao's men have been checked out.
赵爷身边那几个人都已经查过了
They're all clean.
是干净的
What's left
现在唯一没查的
is people in this house.
便是这座公馆了
Uncle will be back later.
表姨父晚一点会回来
He asked us
他让你我一起
to vet everyone first.
将家中之人全部过一遍
Is that so?
确定吗
Yes.
确定了
It's much easier
表姨正好不在家
whilst Aunt is away.
有些事比较好办
Were she here,
太太要是知道
she'd have another heart attack.
心脏病又要犯了
I'm just doing what Uncle says.
我只是替表姨父办事罢了
Miss Feng,
冯先生
I'm afraid you'll have to
怕是也要委屈你一下
answer a few questions, too.
你也需要被问话
Me?
我吗
Leave her out of it.
她不用了
What else is there
她还有什么事
that we don't know about her?
是我们没有查清楚的
Certain details about the night
孙少清出走那一夜
Sun Shaoqing escaped remain unclear.
还有许多事情都没有问过她
You can ask me.
问我不就好了
I was drunk that night
那天晚上在后院
and tried to pull a stunt on her
我缠着她发酒疯
only to get slapped in the backyard.
挨了她一个耳光
Almost everyone in the house saw it.
大半个容府的人都看到了
Jiashang...
嘉上
Miss Feng,
先生
you shouldn't be interrogated.
我不想你接受审问
It's not an interrogation,
不是审问
but an inquiry.
只是询问而已
She'll be fine
冯先生若同此事无关
if she's not involved.
自然也不会冤枉她
I thought she had been ruled out.
她的嫌疑应该已经排除了
Well,
那日
new leads have turned up.
后来又出现了许多疑点
Maybe Miss Feng can be of help.
还是需要再请教冯先生的
Xiucheng,
表哥
you heard me.
我说得很清楚了
It's fine.
没关系
Mr. Yang,
杨先生
I'll cooperate.
我愿意接受你的审问
Relax, Miss Feng.
冯小姐不用紧张
Uncle got this machine from the British
这是表姨父从英国人那里
for polygraph tests
得来的一套测谎仪
based on people's pulse and heartbeat.
用来测一下脉搏 心跳
You'll be safe.
对身体不会有任何伤害
Miss Feng,
先生
you don't have to do this.
你不用勉强
We can stop it anytime
如果有什么不舒服
if you feel uncomfortable.
我们随时可以停止
I can do it, Jiashang.
没事的 嘉上
Jiashang,
嘉上你放心
Uncle wants
表姨父吩咐了
everyone in this house
今天要用这台仪器
to get tested.
把家里所有的人都测一遍
Miss Feng is only the first one.
冯先生只不过是第一个罢了
Whatever.
别啰嗦了
Just do it.
赶紧开始吧
What's your name?
请说一下你的姓名
Feng Shizhen.
冯世真
Age.
年龄
23.
二十三岁
Members of your family.
家中有什么人
My parents and elder brother.
父母和大哥
Did someone send you
冯先生你来容家
to the Rong's?
可曾受过什么人的指使
No.
没有
I came because I needed a job.
我只是来找一份工作
Did you
是否
leak information to others?
传递过情报
No.
没有
Did you say anything to your family?
同家人也没谈论过吗
I'm here to get paid.
我只是来打工的
Gossiping around would do me no good.
用不着在背后嚼东家的舌根
Miss Feng,
冯先生
did you ever encourage
你是否有鼓动过
Sun Shaoqing to escape?
孙少清离家出走
Yes.
有过
She saw me as a close friend
她视我为知己
and shared her pain with me constantly.
频繁地向我吐露痛苦
I felt bad for her
我也很同情她
and tried to comfort her
所以就尽力地去开导她
and cheer her up.
鼓励她
I mean,
说真的
knowing her condition,
以她这样的情况
any compassionate individual
但凡是有同情心的
would advise her to leave
都会鼓励她出走
for freedom,
追求自由
not to mention I'm a woman, too.
我们是女人
We're obligated to help each other.
更加应该互相帮助
Men like you wouldn't understand.
你们男人不会懂的
Did you help her plan out
那你可曾帮她安排策划过
the escape?
如何离家出走
No.
没有
We only talked about
我仅仅是和她探讨过玩偶之家
A Doll's House by Ibsen
说了一下
and how women could be
当女性离开家庭
independent from their family.
应该如何立足
Call me selfish all you want,
不怕你们觉得我油滑
but I didn't want to
我也知道
get involved
万一她要离家出走
in her escape plan.
我还是不要沾任何关系的好
Yet whether I liked it or not,
但尽管如此
I was still involved anyway
我不也还是被牵扯了进来
and got fired by Mr. Rong, didn't I?
还被容老爷辞退了一次吗
That wasn't your fault.
这不是你的错
You meant well.
你都是出自一片好心
Miss Feng,
冯先生
did you contact any outsiders for her?
你是否帮她同外人联络过
No.
没有
Did you send out messages for her?
是否帮她传递过消息
Did she say anything about Xitangli?
她同你提过西堂里的事吗
No.
没有
How did you know Xiao Baoli?
肖宝丽你怎么认识的
She's a popular showgirl in the city
肖宝丽是上海滩知名的舞女
on her way to becoming a movie star.
听说现在要拍电影了
How come
像冯先生这样
a college graduate like you
毕业于名校
with a decent job
又有正经工作
made friends with an escort?
怎么会和一个交际花做朋友呢
We have all kinds of friends.
人都有三教九流的朋友
What's wrong with that?
这是什么奇怪的事吗
Sorry, Jiashang,
抱歉嘉上
but I need to hear it from Miss Feng.
我想听冯先生自己解释
It's simple.
原因很简单
When my family was in distress
之前家里
and we were
遭灾欠了债
knee-deep in debt,
还不起
I thought I could be a showgirl
所以我一度想去舞场
to make money.
做舞女来还债
Then I met Xiao Baoli
我第一次去跳舞场的时候
the first time I went to the club.
认识了肖宝丽
She kept telling me that was a bad idea
宝丽一直劝我不要冲动
that
她告诉我
once I got in,
下水容易
I could never be out.
上岸难
To help me,
所以她介绍了一个
she referred me to a decent moneylender,
比较靠谱的放债人
Mr. Xiong.
叫熊三爷
You probably know him, Mr. Yang.
杨先生估计也听说过他
He offered me cheap loans
他给的利息比较低
and
偶尔
extensions occasionally.
还会给我们家宽限上几天
That was
我就是这样
how Baoli and I became friends.
跟宝丽做了朋友
Identity has nothing to do with friendship.
有时候友谊是不分良贱的
It's true
没错
that Xiao Baoli is an escort
肖宝丽确实是交际花
but she's an upright woman
但是她内心光明磊落
and a loyal friend.
做人有情有义
I trust her
我视她为知己
and I don't think
而且
our friendship is wrong.
我也不觉得跟她交往有任何不妥
Sometimes,
有时候
good or bad is only an idea away.
很多决定都是在一念之间的
If Baoli didn't stop me,
如果当初宝丽没有劝我
I could very well be
那也许今天
a showgirl like her in the club now.
我也只是百乐门里的一个舞女罢了
Mr. Jiashang might meet me there
大少爷和朋友去玩
when he and his friends went clubbing.
也许还会认识我
We'd dance
或许我们还能开开心心地
and have fun together
跳上一场舞
and then go our separate ways.
曲终人散
We wouldn't remember
我记不住一个客人
or mean anything to each other.
你也想不起一个舞女
See?
你看
One decision
一个决定
could change everything.
真的能影响一生的命运
Enough.
够了
Let's call it a day.
今天就到这里吧
One last question.
最后一个问题
Has Miss Sun contacted you
孙小姐离家之后
ever since she left?
可曾再跟你联系过
No.
没有联系过
I'm worried about her.
其实我还挺担心她的
I wonder how she is.
不知道她自己在外面好不好
After all,
毕竟
a young girl like her
她是一个很单纯的女孩子
could be an easy target.
我也怕她会遇到坏人
Thank you for your cooperation.
谢谢冯先生配合
No further questions for now.
暂时没有其他问题了
No problem.
应该的
I'm fine.
没事的
You look worse than me.
你怎么比我还紧张
The past is the past.
我是不想你想起
It shouldn't bother you again.
过去不开心的事
I can handle it.
没事的
It's probably better
有些事情
to get those things off my chest.
说出来反而好
Is Jiashang
就这样
still going to marry Miss Du
嘉上还能老老实实的
at this stage?
去和杜小姐结婚
Let's go.
走吧
Yang Xiucheng and I
待会儿
are going to question the servants next.
我要和杨秀成审问一下家里的下人
It's a lot of work.
可能会有点乱
No time for the class.
今天的课就不上了
Just go back to your room
你在屋子里待着吧
and stay inside.
没什么事情就不要出来了
Sure.
好
Got it.
我知道了
Butler Zhang.
张管事
Yes.
少爷
Gather all our servants.
召集一下家里的下人
Mr. Yang and I need to question them.
我和杨先生等会儿要问话
Tell Fanglin and Fanghua
还有和芳林芳桦也说一声
to stay in their rooms.
没什么事情就别出来乱跑了
Yes, sir.
好的 少爷
Miss Feng.
先生
I have a question for you.
其实我也有个问题要问你
Why did you
那天
ask me to dance that day?
你为什么要请我跳舞
You tell me
你觉得
why a woman
一个女人请一个男人跳舞
asked a man to dance.
需要什么理由
Miss Feng!
先生
Fanglin?
芳林
Do you know what's happening?
你知道大哥他们干吗去了吗
There seems to be a mole in the Residence.
好像是府里出了奸细
Mr. Yang and Mr. Jiashang are checking the servants.
杨先生大少爷要清查一下下人
Why aren't you in your rooms?
你们怎么不回屋里去啊
I think
我看他们的样子
it's going to take a while.
好像要折腾一阵子
Why would someone plant a mole?
家里怎么会进奸细呢
What do we have here?
咱们家有什么可打探的
It's probably nothing.
别怕
Your family business is doing too well.
肯定容府生意做大了
Maybe some competitor
有人起了歪心思
is performing corporate espionage.
想要打探一些商业机密
Why not call the police to arrest him?
那怎么不叫巡捕房的人来抓
We don't know who that person is yet.
总要先查出来是谁啊
Besides,
再说了
this is
这件事情
a sensitive matter.
涉及到贵府的隐私
Your father would want to
我觉得令尊大人
keep it in a tight circle
肯定是不想把事情闹大了
for the sake of your family's image.
免得让旁人看笑话了
I want to go take a look.
我想去看一看
Don't.
别了吧
Uncle Zhang just said
刚才张叔还叮嘱我们
to stay in our rooms.
让我们在房间等着呢
Ignore him.
你怕什么
We don't need to listen to a servant.
他不过是个管事的
I just want to look at it.
再说了 我就去看一眼
What could possibly go wrong?
能出什么大不了的事
Are you coming?
你去不去
Or I'll go without you.
不去我自己去了
Just take a look and go.
那就一眼
Deal.
好
See you, Miss Feng.
那先生我们先走了
Let's go.
走
Hold on.
等等
I'll join you.
那我陪你们一起去吧
Come.
来
Did you send out messages for Miss Sun?
你是否帮孙小姐向外传递过消息
I...
我
I... I...
我我
I... I... I didn't.
我 我 我没有
I swear!
我真没有啊
Don't do this!
饶了我
Fanglin.
姐
Miss Feng,
冯先生
what's going on?
到底发生什么事了
Jiashang looks so serious.
大哥这个样子好凶啊
I'm not sure.
我也不大清楚
It must be something big.
应该是很重要的事情吧
What is Xiucheng saying?
秀成哥哥说什么了呀
I can't make it out.
这听不清楚
Girls,
既然听不清楚
let's go back.
咱们就先回去吧
One more minute, please.
先生 再让我看一会儿
Just one minute.
就一会儿
Let me ask you again.
我再问你一次
Did you steal money from us?
是否偷拿过府上的钱
No.
没有
Mr. Jiashang.
大少爷
You're...?
姓名
Guo Dazhuang.
俺叫郭大壮
I came three years ago.
俺是三年前来这儿的
My uncle Guo Youfu was the guarantor
给俺作保的是俺叔叔郭有福
who died last year.
去年也去世了
Stick to the question.
问你什么你就回答什么
Don't go off topic.
别那么多废话
Did you steal money from us?
你偷拿过府上的钱财吗
No.
没有
Or anything else from us?
偷拿过府里的东西吗
Did you talk to
你跟孙少清小姐
Miss Sun Shaoqing?
可有过接触
Miss Sun?
孙小姐
I'm just a menial.
俺是个粗人
I'd never go near the ladies.
怎么可能跟小姐们有接触啊
Did you leak information to others?
可有将府内之事告与外人
No.
没有
I'm going to ask you again.
我再问你一次
Did you leak information about the Residence
可曾将府上之事
to others?
告与外人
Never... I swear.
俺 俺真没有
Liar!
撒谎
Mr. Jiashang,
大少爷
I'm telling the truth.
真的没有
I know my position. I...
我就是一下人 我
I... I couldn't have known anything
就平时听后院的老妈子
except for maids' small talk.
唠唠家常
Did you take money from outsiders?
你是否拿过外人的钱财
No.
没有
Why would I?
好端端的
I don't work for them.
我拿人钱干啥呀
If you didn't,
没拿钱
how did you pay your mother's medical bills?
你母亲的病是怎么医治的
Seize him!
抓住他
Miss Fen! Help!
先生 快来人啊
Guo Dazhuang,
郭大壮
let Miss Feng go!
放了冯先生
There's no need to do this.
我们有话好好说
Do I look like a fool?
你们真当我傻是吧
People died in your hands
你们容家处理的人
could overfill the Suzhou River.
都能把苏州河给填了
What do you want?
你到底想怎么样
Get me a car.
给俺准备一辆车
Keep the engine running and doors open.
不准熄火 不准关车门
No funny business,
要是敢有小动作
or I'll slit her throat!
俺把这女人脖子给割了
Guo Dazhuang,
郭大壮
I'll go get the car.
我现在帮你备车
Don't hurt her.
你别乱来啊
Put your guns away.
把枪放下
Stay back!
退后
Don't move!
都别动啊
Where's my car?
车呢
Calm down.
你冷静一点
Nobody moves!
都站那儿
Don't move!
都别动
Sir,
大哥
I don't even know you.
咱们无冤无仇
Please let me go.
请你放开我吧
Shut up!
闭嘴
Don't move!
都别动
Miss Feng!
先生
Did he hurt you?
先生 没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
Is that a cut?
受伤了
Just a flesh wound.
一点皮肉伤
Don't worry.
没关系
Mr. Jiashang,
大少爷
what's next?
现在怎么办
What are you waiting for?
还愣着干吗
Go get a doctor!
赶紧去叫大夫
Get up!
起来
Jiashang,
嘉上
what about him?
他怎么处理
Stop his bleeding.
先给他止血
I'll handle him later.
等会儿再审他
Watch him closely.
盯紧点儿
Don't let him kill himself.
防他自尽
- Yes!
是
Move!
走
- Miss Feng!
先生
- Come. - I got you.
来
Careful.
慢点
Miss Feng!
先生
Weren't you told to stay in your rooms?
谁让你们下楼的
We...
我们
We had to take a look.
我们就是想去看一眼
This is huge.
再说了家里发生这么大的事
Why didn't you tell us about it?
为什么不告诉我们
No reason!
哪有这么多为什么
I kept it from you
不让你们参与
to protect you.
就是想保护你们的安全
Look what happened!
你们看
Miss Feng
不听话的后果
wouldn't be there anytime
冯先生替你们承担了
to pay for your recklessness!
那下次呢
Jiashang,
大哥
we don't want this more than you do.
我们也不是故意的
Miss Feng,
冯先生
I'm so sorry about what happened.
对不起 连累你了
Miss Fang,
先生
it's my fault.
对不起
Don't blame yourself.
没事的
It's over.
没事
Mr. Jiashang,
大少爷
I'm fine.
我没事的
It's just a small cut.
只是点皮肉伤
It'll be gone in a few days.
养几天就好了
Let's go back, Fanglin.
姐姐 我们先回房吧
Get some rest, Miss Feng.
那不打扰先生休息了
See you.
快回去吧
Jiashang,
嘉上
I can take care of myself.
你不用担心我
Just do what you got to do.
赶紧忙你的正事去吧
Isn't Mr. Yang waiting for you
刚才杨先生
to interrogate Guo Dazhuang?
不是说还要去审郭大壮吗
Alright.
好
See you later.
那我晚点来看你
Guo Dazhuang.
郭大壮
He must be
他应该就是七爷
working for Boss, too.
安插在容家的另一枚棋子
Does he know my identity?
他 知道我的身份吗
Jiashang,
嘉上
once you find out the truth,
如果有一天你知道了真相
are you going to shoot me
会不会像刚才那样举着枪
the way you just did without hesitation?
毫不留情地对着我扣动扳机
I know you can hear me.
我知道你醒着
Wake up,
你要装死
or don't bother ever again,
还不如真死
you hear?
你说是不是
Your life depends on
你的死活
how well you cooperate.
取决于你接下来的表现
Let's say
我在想
you're a gardener
或许你真的是一个
with no access to the inner courtyard
进不了宅院的花匠
or important information,
那情报定然也不是你偷的
but
但是
you could be the messenger.
你是那个将情报传递出去的人
Who's behind you?
你背后的同伙是谁
Say it.
告诉我
I don't know.
俺不知道
I really don't.
不知道
But
那意思
that person does exist,
就是有这个人
correct?
是吧
I'll ask you again.
我再问你一遍
Who is it?
那个人是谁
Mr. Jiashang,
大少爷
I swear I have no idea!
我真的不知道啊 大少爷
I'm begging you!
我
Please spare me!
你 你就饶了我这一次吧
Please, Mr. Jiashang!
大少爷 我求求你
I won't do it again.
饶了我这一次吧
My mother still needs me!
我家里面还有老娘啊
Spare me, please!
大少爷 我求求你了
Mr. Jiashang,
大少爷
I'm begging you!
我求求你了
how about some torture?
要不要动刑
That's not my style.
我不喜欢勉强
Leave him here
既然他不说
until he wants to talk.
那就关到他说为止
Yes.
是
Mr. Jiashang!
大少爷
Please let me go!
大少爷你饶了我吧 大少爷
How do you feel?
伤还疼吗
Much better now.
好多了
Come on in.
进来吧
Sorry about the mess.
屋里挺乱的
I haven't got to tidy the room.
还没收拾呢
He scared you, didn't he?
你今天被吓到了吧
I can't stop thinking about it.
其实还没缓过来
But
估计
I'll be fine after some sleep.
一会儿睡一觉就能好一些
Have you had lunch?
你吃午饭了吗
Xiao Yu brought me wontons.
刚才小玉送了馄饨过来
They look delicious.
看着挺好吃的
You can have some.
我给你拿
I'm terrified!
我好害怕
I can't stand more losses.
差点重蹈当年的覆辙
I lost
今天
my brother years ago on this day.
是我弟弟的忌日
You had a brother?
你弟弟
That year,
那年
I was twelve
我十二岁
and Jiaxin was eight.
辛弟八岁
We were studying at a church school.
我们俩都在教会小学念书
Usually, Mrs. Rong
放学后
would pick us up,
太太总是会亲自来接我们
but she was needed elsewhere that day.
那天太太恰好有事没来
There was a foreign circus in town.
大世界新来了一个西洋的杂耍团
Our attendant
跟着我们的听差
had been paid by someone else.
早就被外人收买了
He said he'd take us to see the circus.
他哄着我们出去玩
I didn't suspect a thing
我那时候又蠢又贪玩
and left with him with my brother.
就带着我弟弟去了
Rong Dingkun will give me anything
容定坤
to get his two sons back.
老子要什么他不给啊
Write to your father.
给你爹写封信
Oh.
让他拿钱来赎你们
Do it.
写
Don't write anything else,
别给我耍花招听见没有
When help was on the way to get us out,
后来家里面来解救我们
those kidnappers decided to flee.
劫匪准备潜逃
Boss,
大哥
people are coming.
他们赶过来了
They called the police, too.
还有警察呢
Let's get out of here.
走 先撤
Come on. Let's go.
快快快 走
Boss,
大哥
those two boys
带两个孩子
will slow us down.
我们跑不远的
I'll take care of the elder one.
我先解决大的 来
Father! Mother!
爹 娘
Help!
救命
The other kidnapper had me.
我当时被另外一个绑匪抓着
I saw Jiaxin was stifled to death bit by bit
我看着辛弟一点点被捂死
but couldn't do anything about it.
却什么也做不了
Originally,
其实在逃走之前
they planned
那两个绑匪商量过
to kill me
他们想杀了大的
and take Jiaxin away,
带走小的
but then he started to cry aloud.
要不是辛弟在途中哭闹起来
If he hadn't,
死的那个
I would've been the dead one.
就是我
Those kidnappers
那是绑匪歹毒无情
killed your brother in cold blood.
草菅人命
Neither of you should've suffered that.
你们都不应该死
Your brother didn't die because of you.
并不是他的死换来了你的命
As you know,
想必你也知道
Mrs. Rong hates my guts.
太太很厌恶我
But back then,
其实在我小的时候
she wasn't like that.
太太对我挺好的
She'd read me bedtime stories
她还给我念故事书
and tuck me in.
晚上哄我睡觉
All that ended
可是辛弟死后
on the day Jiaxin died.
她就变了
She's been blaming me for his death since then.
她把辛弟的死归结在我身上
She isn't wrong, though.
她也没有怪错
If I hadn't taken him out,
要是我那天没有带着辛弟出去玩
none of that would've happened.
那一切都不会发生
You were a kid yourself.
你那个时候不过是个孩子
Jiashang,
嘉上
those kidnappers
伤害你弟弟的
killed your brother,
是绑匪
not you.
而不是你
You're the victim, too,
你也是受害者
only with better luck.
只是相对幸运罢了
Don't feel guilty
幸存者
about being the survivor.
没有罪
But others thought differently.
可是他们都在怪我
Mrs. Rong wanted me gone.
太太视我为眼中钉
Relatives said nasty things about me.
亲戚们在背后议论纷纷
My father...
我爹
He kicked me out in the end.
他干脆把我送走了
You're not alone.
你不孤单的
You'll get back
过去失去的
what you've lost.
未来会全部拥有回来的